# Ruilong Li

2121 Berkeley Way, Berkeley, CA 94704

Mountain View, USA

Los Angeles, USA

Aug 2019 - May 2021

I am a 4th-year Ph.D. student at UC Berkeley, advised by Angjoo Kanazawa. My current research interests widely spread in Computer Vision & Graphics & Machine Learning, especially on the tasks of generation and reconstruction in the 3D world via information from 2D images.

### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D - University of California, Berkeley Computer Science	$egin{array}{ll} {f Aug.} & {f 2021-Present} \ & Berkeley, \ USA \end{array}$
M.Eng - Tsinghua University  Computer Science and Technology	<b>Aug. 2016</b> – <b>May 2019</b> <i>Beijing, China</i>
B.Sc - Tsinghua University  Mathematics and Physics	Aug. 2012 – May 2016 Beijing, China
RESEARCH POSITIONS	
Research Intern, NVIDIA Research	May 2023 – Present
Working with Francis Williams and Sanja Fidler	Santa Clara, USA
Research Intern, Meta Reality Lab	May 2021 – Dec 2021
Working with Christoph Lassner	$Sausalito,\ USA$
Research Intern, Google Research	May 2020 - Jan. 2021

## ACADEMIC SERVICES

Working with Shan Yang and Angjoo Kanazawa

Research Assistant, USC Institute for Creative Technologies

Reviewer: CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, ACCV, WACV, 3DV, EuroGraphics, Siggraph Asia, ToG, TPAMI, TIP

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Working with Hao Li

- 14. Li, R., Fidler, S., Kanazawa, A. and Williams, F. "NeRF-XL: Scaling NeRFs with Multiple GPUs." In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2024. [link]
- 13. Li, R., Gao H, Tancik M and Kanazawa, A. "Nerfacc: Efficient sampling accelerates nerfs." In International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023. [link]
- 12. Xu, C., Wu, B., Hou, J., Tsai, S., Li, R., Wang, J., Zhan, W., He, Z., Vajda, P., Keutzer, K. and Tomizuka, M., 2023. "NeRF-Det: Learning Geometry-Aware Volumetric Representation for Multi-View 3D Object Detection." In International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023. [link]
- 11. Tancik, M., Weber, E., Ng, E., Li, R., Yi, B., Wang, T., Kristoffersen, A., Austin, J., Salahi, K., Ahuja, A. and Mcallister, D., "Nerfstudio: A modular framework for neural radiance field development." In ACM SIGGRAPH 2023 Conference Proceedings (pp. 1-12) 2023. [link]
- 10. Gao, H., Li, R., Tulsiani, S., Russell, B. and Kanazawa, A. "Monocular dynamic view synthesis: A reality check." In Conference and Workshop on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022. [link]
- 09. Li, R., Tanke, J., Vo, M., Zollhöfer, M., Gall, J., Kanazawa, A. and Lassner, C. "TAVA: Template-free animatable volumetric actors." In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022. [link]
- 08. Yu, A., Li, R., Tancik, M., Li, H., Ng, R., and Kanazawa, A. "Plenoctrees for real-time rendering of neural radiance fields." In International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021. [link]
- 07. Li, R.\*, Yang, S.\*, Ross, A. D. and Kanazawa, A., "AI Choreographer: Music Conditioned 3D Dance Generation with AIST++." In International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021. [link]
- 06. Li, R.\*, Xiu, Y.\*, Saito, S., Huang, Z., Olszewski, K. and Li, H., "Monocular real-time volumetric performance capture." In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020. [link]
- 05. Li, R., Olszewski, K., Xiu, Y., Saito, S., Huang, Z., and Li, H., "Volumetric human teleportation." In ACM SIGGRAPH Real-Time Live!, 2020. [link]

04. Li, R.\*, Bladin, K.\*, Zhao, Y.\*, Chinara, C., Ingraham, O., Xiang, P., Ren, X., Prasad, P., Kishore, B., Xing, J. and Li, H., "Learning formation of physically-based face attributes." In *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2020. [link]

03. Wu, X., Li, R., Zhang, F.L., Liu, J.C., Wang, J., Shamir, A. and Hu, S.M., 2019. "Deep portrait image completion and extrapolation." IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, 29, pp.2344-2355. [link] 02. Zhang, S.H., Li, R., Dong, X., Rosin, P., Cai, Z., Han, X., Yang, D., Huang, H. and Hu, S.M., "Pose2seg: Detection free human instance segmentation." In *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2019. [link] 01. Wang, M., Yang, G.Y., Li, R., Liang, R.Z., Zhang, S.H., Hall, P.M. and Hu, S.M., "Example-guided style-consistent image synthesis from semantic labeling." In *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2019. [link]

## **AWARDS & HONORS**

**ACM SIGGRAPH interview** 

- "We're One Step Closer to Consumer-accessible Immersive Teleportation" (link)

BAIR Research Ignition Award, UC Berkeley	2021
Best Show Award, ACM SIGGRAPH  - "Volumetric human teleportation", Siggraph Real-time Live!	2020
Best Demo Award, China Multimedia Conference	2017
Kwang-Hua Scholarship, Tsinghua University	2014 2012
National Top 200 $(0.04\%)$ , Chinese Physics Olympiad (CPhO)	
INVITIED TALKS & INTERVIEWS	
Interview / Podcast  - "Radiance Field and Gaussian Splatting" (link)	Aug. 2024
EpicGames Research invited talk  - "Reconstructing Dynamic Objects from Video Captures via Neural Rendering"	Jun. 2023
Tencent AI Lab invited talk  - "Acceleration Techniques and Toolbox for Neural Radiance Field"	Dec. 2022
Adobe Research invited talk  - "Learning to Digitize Human Performance"	Sep. 2021
MPI invited talk  - "AI Choreographer: Learn to dance with AIST++" (link)	Feb. 2021
USC Viterbi Magazine interview  - "Connecting People in a Distanced World" (link)	Jan. 2021

Oct. 2020